Jeff Brozena

jeff@brozena.net	+1 (570)335-8269

SUMMARY

An analyst and teacher with 5+ years in strategic alignment/systems integration, change management, and analytical business operations. With more than 50,000 appointments seen per year and rare downtime, I stewarded the group from paper-based record-keeping to full digitization, and was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. I leveraged software to catalyze systemic organizational change at scale.

EDUCATION

The Pennslylvania State University

Aug 2021 — present

PhD - Informatics

The Pennsylvania State University BS - Information Sciences & Technology

EXPERIENCE

Wellbeing and Health Innovation Lab, College of IST - Research Support

Sep 2019 - Aug 2021

 Developing a conceptual and technical framework in Python to detect mental health states using multi-modal data streams reflecting online activities.

The Smilist Management - Manager of Optimization

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

- Discovered, documented, and re-engineered core business processes at dental service organization containing 20+ locations in the New York metro area.
- Conducted root cause analyses via individual/group interviews after quickly establishing rapport with stakeholders at all levels of management.
- · Reduced city and state compliance risk at all sites.
- · Drafted requirements for in-house analytics platform.

Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry - Practice Operations

Aug 2012 — Nov 2017

- Completed an end-to-end digital transformation of one of the country's largest privately-held multi-site Medicaid pediatric dental groups while it continued to serve over 40,000 children annually.
- Stabilized and made legible all business processes, clinical records, and accounting systems for accurate third-party valuation resulting in the sale of the business.
- Fostered trust with multiple owners, serving as strategic counsel in technical and nontechnical capacities.
- Completed a sequence of practice management software data conversions at three sites, coordinating between internal management and multiple external vendors.
- Identified and voiced the cultural need for standardization of business processes and technical systems, earning the trust of ownership, management, and 100+ employees.
- Integrated best-of-breed dental analytics platform into daily workflows, creating conditions for legacy understandings to evolve into data-driven decision-making.
- Invited to present to 5,000 pediatric dentists at the American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry on the subjects of digitization and compliant record-keeping.

Bedrock Technology - Technician

Jan 2012 - Aug 2012

AWARDS

Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

Apr 2011

Emerging Scholars Fellowship, Active Minds, Inc.

Jan 2011

SKILLS

Leadership: Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

Digital transformation: Intermediate knowledge of Data Analysis (Python, pandas, SQL), Data Visualization (Altair, Matplotlib, Seaborn), Analytical operations management, Software training, Software integration, Transformational change management, Strategic planning

Healthcare IT: Working knowledge of HIPAA Privacy/Security Rule, HEDIS, Medicaid / Managed Care, Electronic data interchange (835/837), Vender selection/relations, Clinical decision support